-==http://www.ragbear.com==-
Edited & correction:lfellix [freelance]
Gwenda?
Have you...
..retyped the chapter on Medici?
Yes, Mr Argyle.
It's in the tray.
Ah. Good.
Good.
Then tomorrow we can move on.
On to the modern era.
Yes, Mr Argyle.
Er...could you...
..turn that off, please, Gwenda?
Mother...
why do we have
to go through this charade,
where I have to confess my sins to you
like you're some sort of female Pope?
Give me the money and I'll go!
What's it for, Jacko?
It doesn't matter what it's for!
Is it for business, drugs?
Is that Jacko again?
- That's Jacko.
- It is not illegal!
-==http://www.ragbear.com==-
Just tell me what it's for, Jacko.
Mother. Mother...
do you think I could come here
and humiliate myself again
If it wasn't important,
if I... look, If I had anywhere else to go?
Don't you think
I have any shame, Mother?
No, I don't, Jacko.
I think you're shameless.
You've always treated me like a bank
that will dig you out
of every hole you've got into.
- Philip.
- Thank you, darling.
You can spare the money.
That is not the point.
The point is, Jacko...
Next time I see you...
I wonder how much he needs this time.
This is different.
Whatever your brother wants,
she will give it to him.
How much?
Two-and-a-half thousand pounds.
Don't do that!
And if I don't give him
the first 500 tomorrow,
he's going to kill me.
Some of the thugs that work for him
will pour a bottle of whisky
down my throat,
prop me behind the wheel of a car
and roll me into a bloody crossing.
The next time you see me, I'll be dead!
Is that what you want?
I know you keep that sort of money
in the house.
I'd like to meet this
bookmaker friend of yours, please.
That's not how it's gonna work.
I am telling you how it's going to work, boy!
I want this bookmaker to come here,
to Sunny Point tomorrow.
And if what you say is true,
he and I will discuss a way
of repaying your debt.
Don't mess with this man, Mother.
You don't know --
What are you doing, Kirsten?
I am standing here listening
to the argument.
Mother, this man is not going to
come here like a bloody kid at school
to discuss over some playground spat!
He's going to come up here with a gun!
ORDEAL BY INNOCENCE
This is not a game, woman.
Give me the money, I have nowhere else to go.
Will this ever end, Jacko?
...all the advantages you had,
All the money and I have poured into you.
What have you become?
A little man.
You're a bitch!
- Give it to me!
- No.
- No more!
- Give it to me, I need it!
I think you should leave now, Jacko.
Give me the money now, or I will kill you!
Good God!
Jacko!
Get off!
I swear to God...
I swear to God, she is dead!
Get out, Jacko!
Go on!
Jacko!
Jacko, wait!
I'm a dead man, Hes.
Calm down. Let's go for a walk, baby.
Has he gone?
He's gone.
Will you tell your person to leave, please?
Sorry?
I'll take the post.
Hum, nine o'clock tomorrow, Gwenda.
Yes, sir.
I didn't give him the money this time, Leo.
No.
Jacko's a bad lot.
He always has been.
Have I done the right thing?
Rachel, you've always done exactly
what you wanted with these children.
I think it's a bit late
to start asking for my advice.
That's all right, Leo.
Once again, I will try to do
the right thing by your children
and I will subsidise you
as you write sub-standard books,
which no-one ever wants to publish,
and I will make the difficult decisions for our family.
You're the biggest parasite of the lot, Leo.
- Mother.
- Not now, Bobby.
We need to confirm what
we're doing about the City trusts.
Sort it out yourself, Bobby.
Sometimes I feel I should never
have bothered with you and your brother.
Ah, Kirsten.
Have you, er... seen Mary?
Your wife will be down
at the lodge, Mr Durrant.
Right.
Maybe you should go to her.
I think I'll just have a little drink first.
Oh, God! Is she dead?
Is she dead?
Go and fetch Leo.
- Hello.
- What number, sir?
I need the police.
"Murder at Sunny Point
"Son arrested"
I don't know what
you're smiling for, Mr Argyle.
I have seven witnesses who heard
you threaten to kill your mother
not long before she died.
So what?
I didn't do it.
These same family members
also testify that you attacked her
because she wouldn't pay off
your gambling debts.
Look, everyone between here and Bristol
knows the old girl kept a stash in her desk.
Now, I'm not a detective, Inspector Huish,
I wouldn't dare presume.
But the whole thing
looks like a burglary to me.
Mum was in the wrong place
at the wrong time.
Which the coroner says
was about eight o'clock.
Was it?
Where were you at eight o'clock, Jacko?
Hitch-hiking.
Between Redquay and Drymouth.
Who was driving the car?
I don't know.
He was about 35, dark hair, drove
a dark blue Morris Minor.
Talked a lot about eels.
Very boring. What can I say?
He dropped me outside the pub at 8.15.
You're a cocky little swine, aren't you?
From time to time.
Is this yours?
Yep.
The Southern Bank in Drymouth
issued these two five-pound notes
to your mother yesterday morning.
Their serial numbers
are from the batch of 100 pounds
that your mother collects each month
to top up float she has on these days.
Yes, she gave it to me after we'd argued.
Your family are sure she didn't give you
any money, Jacko.
Well, she did. So that's that.
Isn't it?
What you've got to do now, mate,
is your job.
You've got to find the guy
who gave me the lift.
Your alibi's a lie.
I did not murder my mother!
You've lived a life of lies, haven't you, Jacko?
SUNNY POINT MURDER: A LIFE OF LIES
JACK ARGYLE TO HANG
TWO YEARS LATER
"Dear Miss Marple,
It's a while since I wrote.
But as you know, I regard time
I spent in service with you
as the time from which my life began.
You gave me the confidence
to train for a profession
and seek my place in the world.
I hope I don't embarrass you, Miss Marple,
when I write that you are
the closest to family I have.
Fate has dealt me a curious hand
since I left you.
But I am at last to be married,
having found happiness in life
which I always thought would elude me.
I would love it if it were possible for you
to share my day of happiness with me."
"Dearest Gwenda,
of course I remember you,
and would love to come to wedding.
As I grow older,
nothing brings me more pleasure
than to see young people
I am fond of find happiness.
Of all the girls who have come to me
from the orphanage,
It was you who underwent
the greatest transformation.
And I have often wondered
what opportunities you have made
with your life.
As the wedding is on Saturday,
could I possibly travel down to Devon
early on Thursday morning
to give me time to recover from the train?"
She can come.
Oh, Leo!
Leo! She can come!
Ah, how wonderful!
That's marvellous. When's she coming down?
Erm...yes, next we have...
we have the arctic fox.
NATIONAL GEOGRAPHIC...
That's Alopex lagopus.
SOCIETY, LONDON
There she is.
Cuddly little lass,
unless you actually try to cuddle her
when she might basically,
sort of, bite your hand off.
So I suppose she's not...
she's not cuddly at all, really.
No, the thing that's interesting,
actually, really interesting
about Alopex lagopus,
is its comparison to
the more common European fox.
So let's have a look at her.
There we...
Ah, no. Sorry, that's er...
I do apologise.
That's actually Miss Frobisher.
She's a colleague of mine on the Hayes...
..Hayes what-d'you-ma-call-it.
There we go. There we go.
Vulpes vulpes.
Now...
as we can see,
these two foxes have adapted to live
in different climates.
And the former one, here,
is er...believe me, very furry.
And has a good supply of body fat.
What helps her to survive
in her very frigid environment...
is her short muzzle
and very thick ears.
I'm so sorry.
I do apologise.
That's..yes. Marjorie, I do hope
you're not with us tonight.
Sorry.
Fascinating talk, Dr Calgary.
I do hope so. Thank you.
It was indeed, Doctor. Most illuminating.
Very kind. Thank you.
EXECUTED
- Miss Marple.
- Gwenda!
Oh, how lovely to see you again!
Yes. Yes.
Well, first of all,
I must apologise for the weather.
And I also must apologise...thank you...
for the um...the final mode of transport
needed to get you over to Sunny Point.
But, you see,
the house is on a little island.
The only way of getting across
is on one of the little boats
which are all named
after Leo's children, the boats.
Oh, yes.
Slow down, slow down.
Let me have a look at you.
You look wonderful.
It's been too long.
I'm so glad
that you could come, Miss Marple.
I can't tell you.
You see, Leo has five grown-up children.
Five!
And you know how intimidating
large families can be,
especially when
they're all holed up together.
But at least I'm going to get person
on my side this weekend.
Oh! It's a bit muddy, isn't it?
Yes, very. Mind your step.
Gwenda, is this the same Sunny Point
that had a tragedy a couple of years ago?
Yes.
Yes, that's right.
Rachel's death was a terrible thing...
But er...it's behind us now.
Anyway, mind your step, Miss Marple,
on this duckboard,
which is very slippy.
DANGER, DEEP WATER
I do hope you're going
to be comfortable, Miss Marple.
That's it. Have you got it?
- Mind the corner.
- You mind the corner.
Hold on. Tina? Tina!
Yes, sir. Yes, Bobby, sir.
Who put these flowers here?
You did, Sergeant Major, sah!
- Did I?
- You did, Bob.
No, I want the roses in here
and I want these ones in the dining room.
Can't the new maid do it?
Get Micky to ask.
He's always looking
for a chance to talk to her.
Hey!
Um...no. Hester, no.
No, we're using
the old dinner service tonight.
We're saving the best for
the wedding day itself. Run away.
Yeah. OK.
How much has all this cost, Bob?
It's great you've arranged it all.
Well, Dad deserves it done right.
- Hello, everybody.
- Hey.
You must be the
much-spoken-about Miss Marple.
Am I? Oh, dear.
These are Leo's sons - Bobby...
- Hello.
- Hello, Bobby.
- Nice to see you.
- And Micky.
- Pleased to meet you.
- Mickey.
And how are you, Mother?
Oh, don't!
May I take your bag, Miss Marple?
Thank you.
These are our two youngest sisters.
- Hester and Tina.
- Hello.
- Hello, Hester.
Tina.
Let's see if Miss Marple
can spot the family resemblance.
You see, Leo and Rachel's children
are adopted.
I see.
The forecast says it's going to rain
all weekend, Gwenda.
You do realise, don't you?
This is Philip.
He's married to our sister Mary.
But we ignore him. He's grumpy.
I'm the grump's wife Mary.
- So many people.
- Oh, and here...
Here is Leo.
Welcome to Sunny Point, Miss Marple.
Thank you.
- House! House?
- A steeple?
- A hat?
- Roof?
- A top?
- Picking up...?
..putting down...?
- A reindeer?
- Pooh sticks?
Eeyore! Eeyore!
The House At Pooh Corner.
Yes!
Philip has smiled!
This is a truly momentous day!
Here we go round the Mulberry Bush?
Spinning?
Carousel?
Do the whole thing, Gwenda.
You're making a hole in carpet.
The maid's just left the room, Micky.
Can we concentrate on Gwenda?
- A bird?
- What's she doing?
- A spectre?
- Ghost story?
- The Turn Of The Screw!
- Yes!
Who's that?
Let the poor man in.
I thought it was a ghost.
How on earth did he make it here
on a night like this?
Poor man!
Who are you?
I'm so sorry, I'm...
I'm very wet.
Very sorry.
Is Mr...
Argyle, Mr Leo Argyle...in the house?
Yes.
My name is Arthur Calgary.
And I'm here to tell you...
- Here.
- Oh, thank you.
Thank you very much, you're a...
you're a very kind and thoughtful lady.
Erm...Yes.
I'm here to tell you...
..that there is no possible way
that your son Jacko
committed that murder, sir.
He's innocent.
And I can prove it.
Yes, I'm... I'm a scientist.
At Cambridge University.
But for the last two years,
I've been in the Arctic.
Have you been
on the Hayes Bentley Expedition?
Back a month. Yes.
But we left, you see, on...
..on...on...
17th October, two years ago.
But the day before, the 16th, I was here.
I was here in Redquay,
saying goodbye to Nanny,
who's retired to a home in the area.
Actually, Nanny's sister's
been very ill recently with psoriasis.
We don't need to hear about
Nanny's sister.
No, no.
So you were in the area
the night my wife was murdered?
Which was at about eight o'clock
in the evening.
Yes.
At that time, I was driving
between Redquay and Drymouth.
- In a dark blue Morris Minor?
- That's right. That's right.
And between ten-to and quarter-past,
I gave a ride to a hitchhiker.
Most eels, well, most Anguilliformes,
prefer to dwell in shallow waters.
Or hide at the bottom layer
of the ocean in tiny holes.
Have you got the time?
My God.
You're the alibi.
I'm the...yes.
The...yeah, what-d'you-ma-call-it.
Who they never found.
And they never found me,
because when they started looking,
I was halfway round the world
looking at lemmings.
Dr Calgary's with you now?
I told him to wait
till we came in the morning.
Is he who he says he is?
I don't think he's a scientist.
He doesn't seem clever.
Checking all his story's dates seem to fit.
It looks like your brother was
telling the truth all along about his alibi.
When can you get here, Inspector?
The morning. We won't get
over the crossing in this weather.
Look, Mr Argyle, Dr Calgary thinks
he is doing a good thing,
rushing to tell your family this.
But while he knows an unnatural amount
about eels and such,
I don't think he knows a lot about people.
How are they all taking the news?
I er...
I thought you'd be pleased to know
that Jacko Argyle isn't a murderer.
We are.
So, let's er...
..jump for joy.
- You are an insensitive man, Dr Calgary.
- Kirsten.
No, what did he think he was doing?
When you looked through the window,
didn't you see a happy family?
I did, I did, and I thought that um...
..what I had to say
would make you happier.
That our brother was
executed for a murder he didn't commit?
Why couldn't you
have just left us all alone?
Yes, thank you, Dr Calgary.
- Come on, Hes.
- Daddy.
Come on.
correction by: lfellix(freelancer)
Well-- I say...
Yeah, what's the quote?
"Nothing is", um... "Nothing is ever"...
I was useless at literature.
"Nothing is settled"...
"Nothing is ever settled until it is settled right"
- Kipling.
- Yes, quite so.
The police have requested
that you leave now.
Oh. In this weather?
They didn't mention the weather.
They just asked you to go.
Right.
It's true, though, isn't it,
what Kipling said?
Think it's true?
Oh, Miss Marple, I think...
If you don't mind,
I do think we ought to leave the family
to themselves for a while.
Of course.
Would you care to have supper in my room?
I'm sure Miss Marple
would prefer her own company.
She's had a long journey.
No, it would be nice to have company.
Thank you.
When did Rachel Argyle realise
she couldn't have children?
Just after she was married.
She was an heiress.
Her father was rich as a king.
She used that money to buy her family.
And bought Viper's Point,
which was original name of estate.
She changed the name to Sunny Point,
and filled it like a fairground
with everything a child might desire.
And over the years,
she bought the children
from deprived backgrounds.
Mary's the eldest, isn't she?
She was from New York.
Slum tenement, parents in jail.
She's always been a particular girl.
Everything proper and in its place.
And her husband, the pilot.
He's a bag of badness, I tell you.
Rachel never liked him.
And she was right.
Why is he in a wheelchair?
Pollo.
18 months ago.
Then after Mary came the twins,
Jacko and Bobby.
Bobby was Jacko's twin?
Oh, yes.
They came from an orphanage,
about the same time I came from Denmark
to take up appointment.
Then Hester was a Catholic girl's shame,
and Micky and Tina during the war.
Micky from the East End,
Tina's mother a...
if you understand what I mean.
They both live in Redquay.
The children were Rachel's obsession,
the well she poured
all her money and attention down.
And her love?
You know, Miss Marple,
Rachel meant well,
but her tragedy was that
I don't think she was capable of love.
At least, not towards her children.
Shall I say what we're all thinking?
Is that a good idea?
Why we're not looking each other in the eye.
Just eat your dinner, Tina.
'Cause if Jacko didn't kill the bitch, who did?
Don't you dare use language
like that against Mother.
I used it behind her back
when she was alive, Mary.
I'll use it when she is dead.
Apologise.
It's what everyone's thinking, Daddy.
Tina!
I think that um...
I think that we should maybe
talk about all this
when the shock has worn off, don't you?
Why not? Let's all talk about the weather,
shall we, Gwenda?
The price of tea?
How very English.
I'm sorry, sir, but Tina is right.
If Jacko didn't murder Rachel,
then which one of your children did?
It was a burglary. Surely?
Like Jacko always said.
I think we should leave
any speculation to the police.
- Police?
- Yes. The police.
And it won't just be Jacko's movements
that night they'll be investigating.
It will be all of us.
Well, I'm going to say It was a burglary.
Well, they'll accept that.
Last time we just told them it was Jacko
and they accepted that straight away.
I don't think we're dealing
with Sherlock Holmes here.
I will not have this talk!
Yes, sir.
Sorry, Dad.
- Sorry, Daddy.
If you'll excuse us.
Did Mrs Argyle leave
any of her fortune to her children?
I know what you're thinking.
You old ladies, you look so benign,
and yet your brain goes ticktock, ticktock,
pouring over the latest murders
in the newspapers
looking for motives.
Well, one has few pleasures left in life.
Rachel left all her fortune in trust
for her children, administered by Bobby.
They are all wealthy,
and can dip into the trust
with his permission at any time.
But at that time, Rachel had stopped
being generous to Jacko.
He had wasted so much on illegal schemes.
We don't know half of what he got up to.
We didn't know he was married.
Jacko was married?
Oh, yes.
She turned up out of the blue
on the day of Rachel's funeral
Yes?
Hello.
I'm Maureen.
Hello, Maureen.
Yeah. Jacko's wife.
No!
Jacko's not married.
My mum said what,
with him committing murder and that,
I should come up to the big house
and you'd see me right.
What is it, Kirsten?
- Jacko's got a wife.
- Lies!
Now that Jacko's going
to be found guilty and all,
I thought I'd come
for you to see me right, Mr Argyle.
- Lies and wickedness.
- Be quiet, Kirsten.
It's a bit early to say
if he's going to be found guilty.
He did have the money, sir.
And she was right, Miss Marple.
He was found with some of the money on him.
The exact same serial numbers.
Jacko was responsible.
I'm certain.
Always a wicked boy.
Her ghost comes back to haunt me.
Once again, Rachel takes away
any chance of happiness.
What do you mean?
You saw how suspicious everyone was
of each other tonight.
Yes, but...
I mean, if Jacko wasn't guilty,
then the police will soon discover who is.
Two years on?
They won't find anything they can use.
And when the police reopen the investigation,
the whole world will be suspicious
of this family.
Excuse me, Bobby.
Have you seen Gwenda?
No-one thought Jacko was innocent, you know.
No.
Unlike everyone else,
he actually was my flesh and blood.
And even I didn't think that.
It was such a cut-and-dried case.
And he was always such a terrible liar.
And violent, if you went against him.
Do you think um...
..Dr Calgary is mistaken?
The day before my brother was...
was executed,
Hes and I visited him in prison.
It's time to say goodbye, Hes.
No!
No, don't say goodbye, Jacko!
No, because I know you didn't do it, Jacko!
Get off me!
Come on, please. Come on.
I've um...
I've made sure that wife of yours
is provided for.
I should have been more like you,
shouldn't I, Bob?
That's what they told me all my life.
"How could twins be so different?"
There's no...
..no chance of an appeal, is there?
It's the money you had
that hangs you, Jack.
Maybe this is the best thing
I've ever done.
It's gone round and round in my head
for two years.
And now...
I think I know what he meant.
I think he knew...who the real killer was.
And he was protecting them.
He was prepared to die for them.
This is ridiculous.
We should have stayed up at the house.
We're better here.
What, so you can murder me as well?
Let's get you out of these wet things.
You have ice in your heart, Mary.
You're capable of murder, I've always
known that about you.
Don't be silly.
Especially - the murder of her.
I loved my mother.
When the police arrive tomorrow,
you'd better get your story straight, my girl
Just remember exactly what you told them
the first time.
Actually um...
..Leo and I are thinking
of postponing the wedding, Miss Marple.
I'm sorry, dear.
Two hours ago, I was happy.
I was so happy that you'd arrived,
happy to be part of a family,
happy to have found him.
And I won't have it taken away from me.
I won't!
Is there anything I can do, Gwenda?
Yes, leave.
That's what you can do.
I think um...
I just need to be on my own for a while.
We can talk at breakfast.
I'm sorry. It's you.
Yes, er...
Crossing seemed rather difficult
in this weather.
The truth is, it's a dangerous crossing.
Indeed.
Indeed, yes.
Tell me, shouldn't...
shouldn't you be inside and...
in the warm?
Do you want another truth, Dr Scientist?
Mother and Jacko dying...
was the best thing
that happened to this family.
They were the ones who brought
unhappiness here.
I loved my brother, but...
without him, we'd become a happy family.
Until you arrived.
We all know it wasn't a burglary,
and if Jacko didn't kill her,
which one of us must be guilty?
Hester?
Hes, are you in here?
Come on, sweetheart, let's get you inside.
But it's not the guilty
that matter, is it, Dr Scientist?
It's the innocent.
The innocent who will suffer now.
If you can't get across,
you might as well come in, too.
The first thing police will do
is try to establish a motive.
Sorry, where am I sleeping?
- In the study.
- The motive's easy.
Who gained most from Mother's death?
Who now lives in her bedroom?
- Gwenda.
- Exactly.
Who's going to share a bed
with her husband?
Are you heading back to London,
Dr Calgary?
Well, er...
I think yes, yes I should, but...
I think also I should stay and put right this...
..this upset that I caused
by blundering in last night.
That young girl Hester
said yesterday that...
it would be the innocent
who would suffer
now the case has been reopened.
How perceptive of her.
Yes, that's what I thought, very perceptive.
What on earth did she mean?
Eighty years ago,
a man called Charles Bravo
was poisoned in his London home.
There were three suspects
his wife, his doctor and his best friend.
Scotland Yard never found enough evidence
to bring any of them to trial,
so all of them - the two who were innocent
as well as the guilty
were branded murderers by society
and had their lives ruined.
They all died prematurely...
..from either suicide or drink.
Goodness.
You're right not to leave, Dr Calgary.
There are innocent lives here
which will be ruined
if the murderer is not found.
And if the police can't find the evidence,
someone else will have to.
I last saw my wife
just before seven o'clock on the night.
This is documented.
What did you and she talk about it?
The decision
not to give Jacko any more money.
We didn't talk for long, but...
it was cordial.
And I will subsidise you
as you write sub-standard books,
which nobody wants to publish.
You're the biggest parasite of the lot, Leo.
The next time I saw her, she was dead.
So you were alone in your room
for that hour and a half?
Yes.
Was the rest of your family in the house
at the time?
Not Tina and Micky.
They have flats over in Redquay.
Jacko's wife?
At that point, we didn't know
Jacko was married, Inspector.
This will cheer him up.
The first edition's arrived, Father.
Ah, thank you. Thank you.
- Well, open it.
- Later, I think.
No, open it now.
Go on.
Mr and Mrs Durrant,
may I see you, please?
It should have been an ecstatic moment.
It still is, isn't it, Pops?
You open it.
What did they ask you in there?
Anything about Tina?
Look at this.
Well.
Mr and Mrs Durrant,
it appears from your statement
of two years ago
that you were in the drawing room
between the time of the argument
and the body's been discovery.
Yes, it was our habit
to spend the evenings here
rather than down at the lodge.
Your wife will be down at the lodge,
Mr Durrant.
Maybe you should go to her.
During that time, you didn't see or hear
anyone go into Mrs Argyle's study?
No.
I knew Jacko never killed her.
I mean, he was a hothead, he was in fights.
Everyone knew that about him, but...
But it...takes a different kind of character
to pick up a weapon and murder someone,
doesn't it, Hester?
A coldness.
Yes, a coldness.
Were you in the house when your mother died?
Yes.
You spoke to Jacko after the argument,
didn't you?
I calmed him down.
I'm a dead man, Hes.
Let's go for a walk, baby.
Were you here, Tina?
I was at work.
In the library in Redquay.
Micky has cold blood in him.
Hester!
No, I love him, I do, Tina.
But he has the coldness.
Micky works in the motor trade in Redquay.
At the time of the murder,
he was collecting a car
from a dealer in Bristol.
He's told the police this.
Yes, but he hated her
more than anyone, Miss Marple.
Well, he could hardly speak to her
without cursing.
You left Sunny Point
before seven o'clock that evening,
and you went straight home?
Yes.
I... I took the post and erm...
posted it.
And then...
yes, home.
Miss Vaughan,
had your friendship with Mr Argyle
begun before his wife's death?
No!
So your relationship with his wife was good?
Yes.
She didn't know you harboured feelings
for her husband?
Er...well...I...
I didn't...at that time...
I didn't have...feelings, as you put it.
For Leo.
We've fallen in love since his wife's death.
In many ways, I've helped him through it.
Let the new maid do that, Kirsten.
I've let her go
for a couple of days, Mr Argyle.
Best keep all this police business
within the family.
Is Gwenda still in with them?
Oh, yes, she'll still be in there,
lying, I imagine.
Lying? About what?
About what friends
she and Mrs Argyle were.
About how you and her
only fell in love after your wife died
Well, it's the truth.
No, it is not, sir.
I've been thinking, Mr Argyle.
I've been thinking about motives.
And Rachel knew
that girl was in love with you.
Rachel had confronted her
before she died,
said she was a cuckoo in the nest.
What's that, Miss Lindstrom?
No doubt, she will deny this, Inspector.
She will try and shore up
the lies she has told you in there
But I heard bad words in this house
between her and Rachel Argyle,
one week before she was murdered.
Listen to me, you little slut!
I see the way you look at him.
We all know about women like you.
You keep him to walk away
from me, so you can...
He doesn't love you.
Leave my husband alone
or I will dismiss you from this house!
What does a sad little woman like you
know about love?
I have to tell this, Gwenda.
Can you deny it?
You want a motive, Inspector?
Then I think this woman heard Jacko shout
"I will kill you. You are dead."
And she knows that
if she kills Rachel that night
Jacko will get the blame.
And she will get the man
and the house she wants.
Can you deny this, Gwenda Vaughan?
The motive, the scheme, the coldness?
Leo? Leo!
Leo!
Thank God you
have not yet married her, Mr Argyle.
Thank God she will not get away with it.
Leo!
Leo?
Leo? Leo?
I didn't do it!
Leo!
You believe me, don't you?
It's that hoop over there now, Hes.
That's right! Come on.
Don't you know how to play by now?
Be quiet, Mary!
Are you admiring my brother's
ability to keep things going, Calgary?
Yes, I was, rather.
He's always organising.
He's organised
the whole of tomorrow's wedding,
if it's to take place.
He's paid for the lot.
Yes, he made his money in the... in the City,
if I'm not mistaken?
Yes.
The only one Mother could be proud of.
Money was important to Mother.
She bought me for 100 pounds, Doctor.
Did you know that?
I was evacuated here during the war.
And afterwards, she bought me
from my natural mother...
for 100 pounds.
From the day I came here...
..all I wanted to do was to go home.
Yes.
It's my turn.
- Stop being such a drip, Hes.
- Bobby.
Inspector.
We haven't been introduced,
but I'm Jane Marple,
an old friend of Gwenda Vaughan's
down for the wedding.
I wish to vouch for her character.
Yes, of course,
she's kind to cats and children
and like her mother, who I presume
was your best friend, she'd never
have done anything like this.
I have no idea who her mother was.
I'm beginning to understand
what Rachel Argyle
was like as a mother,
and I think she, not Gwenda,
is the key to solving this crime, don't you?
Can we stay still for a moment?
I'm too old to trot.
Now, with most crimes
it's the character of the killer
which is most fascinating.
But in this case it's the character
of the victim which reveals more.
- Don't you agree?
- Maybe. Go on.
This is no crime of passion.
It's one of...immaturity.
Of arrested development,
most common to teenage years.
The Argyles lived under the iron control of
their mother even into adulthood.
No wonder Jacko kept his wife a secret.
To get married would be
too much like growing up.
Gwenda Vaughan remains my main suspect.
No, your main suspect is still Jacko.
I'm sure that's what you mean, Inspector.
He was in possession of money
from that desk.
Have you asked yourself how he got it?
Inspector. Miss Marple.
Is there any chance
of a lift to the Swan Hotel?
Yes, of course, Doctor.
- Have you asked yourself?
- I have.
His twin brother thinks
Jacko went to his execution
protecting someone.
Now, he hardly knew Gwenda Vaughan.
Why would he die to protect her?
I'll let you get on.
- Thank you.
- Goodbye.
- Goodbye, Dr Calgary.
Who was that?
Gwenda.
Gwenda?
Yes, come in, Miss Marple.
- You haven't been down to supper, dear...
- No.
- So, I...
- Leo's called off the wedding.
Oh, yes, they're all talking
about it downstairs.
Oh, I bet they are.
I bet they're having a sweepstake on
when the police will arrest me.
They won't arrest you without any evidence.
No, but they suspect me, don't they?
And I haven't got an alibi
for that evening, Miss Marple.
Even Leo suspects me.
But the thing is... No, you see,
I was thinking, that erm...
Rachel's rooms haven't been touched
since she died
and I just thought that, you know, maybe...
Maybe there's something in here
that's been overlooked, you know,
that might point to the killer.
Like a diary or correspondence?
Yes. But I can't find anything.
Surely something like that's more likely
to be found in her study, isn't it?
Yes.
Will you help me, Miss Marple?
The obvious person Jacko
would be protecting would be his wife.
What's she like?
Maureen?
Erm...well, I only saw her once.
Bobby sorted her out financially
and after that no-one in family
ever heard from her again.
Well, it's about time she heard from us.
Is there a safe?
Allow me.
There we are.
That's it.
Where did you learn to do that?
My nephew Raymond has one.
He's always losing the key.
Ah, there.
- Who was it?
- Bobby.
Yes, of course, him.
He's just catching
the early morning train to London.
It's been cleared out.
JOHN CROKER PRIVATE DETECTIVE
What would Rachel be doing
with a private detective?
That's what you must find out tomorrow.
At the Swan Hotel.
There's someone there
who will be willing to help you.
Yes, I was in Mrs Argyle's employ.
But I'm afraid I'm not at liberty
to discuss circumstances.
Confidentiality is my middle name, you see.
Well, yes, I understand that, Mr Croker,
but you see, it's possible you might be
able to help us with investig...
I must stop you there, young lady,
and terminate this interview forthwith.
Because discretion is my middle name.
- I thought you said it was confidentiality.
- Good day.
Wait. Wait, wait. Listen, Mr...
Mr erm... Erm...
whatever your middle name is.
If you don't sit down and answer our questions,
before the end of today,
you'll be having the same questions
put to you by the police
- The police?
- Yes, the police.
I don't like the police.
Well, then, just park yourself there...
and, yes... Thank you.
- The police?
- Yes.
Now, most people
hire a private detective, Mr Croker,
because they're going through a divorce.
So...did Rachel Argyle
ask you to investigate her husband?
No.
I was employed to investigate
another member of her family.
- Who?
- Her son-in-law.
Philip Durrant.
Why?
Well, before his unfortunate illness,
Mr Durrant was what I call a
"leg-over merchant".
Right little man about town.
Rachel Argyle suspected
he'd just married her daughter for her money
and she was right.
That's why she kept tight rein
on her daughter's inheritance
Anyway,
she wanted evidence from me that
would force marriage to end
I provided a large file containing
the names of women,
the dates of his assignations in hotels,
photographs
you know the form
and I delivered it to her a few days
before she died.
Hester.
Hes.
When we first married,
Philip bought a maisonette in Redquay.
- Was he working?
- No, he'd come out of the RAF
and was erm...between ventures.
Never very lucky.
Anyway, Mother took one look
at our little place
and insisted that we came here
to take the lodge.
You erm...
You didn't want to come?
Philip was something that was mine,
Miss Marple.
Not hers.
But it turned out he didn't have
as much money as he said he had
and was eager to come and
escape the mortgage.
Couldn't you take money out of your trust?
Mother would never have given permission.
And now Bobby has that power
and he's also reluctant.
It's been nearly two years since
that awful night, Miss Marple,
and yet we still haven't been able
to move on.
Must have been shocking for you
to have discovered
your mother's body that way.
Well, it was Kirsten
who actually discovered her.
Yes.
And then Philip who phoned the police.
Fortunately, I wasn't there at the time.
It has to be Philip Durrant. He's the killer.
Rachel had confronted him with the...erm...
- Evidence.
- Evidence. Thank you.
From Confidentiality Croker.
And then Philip overheard
Jacko threaten to kill her.
When the house was quiet,
he took his chance to bang her on the head.
We should go back to Sunny Point now
and make a citizen's arrest.
Bang the fellow up.
Erm, why are we seeing a film?
Miss Marple said we had to find Maureen.
Who's Maureen?
- Jacko's wife.
- Right, yes, of course.
Jacko did it, Miss Vaughan
No doubt. He was found with the evidence.
- The...money from the desk?
- That's right.
And he had a nasty side. He...
I was pleased to be rid of him,
if you know what I mean.
- Mm, yes.
- Mum said he was just a charmer, you know?
Women had a thing for him.
Especially older women.
- He could play them like a piano.
- Mm. How do you mean?
Well, he'd flatter them,
get them to fall in love with him,
and he'd sting for money
he needed for some scam or other.
He worked for this car salesman
and got into trouble
when a lot of money went missing.
The salesman's wife was
so besotted with him
that she ended up raiding
her own savings
so that he could give the money back
to the husband.
Could he always get money
out of his mother?
- No.
- Uh. He had to be desperate to go to her.
But he was desperate that night,
Miss Vaughan.
He was very scared.
The bookle was really a gangster
and he was gonna kill him.
I think Jacko owed much more money
than he was letting on.
He was innocent and no-one believed him.
I believe Gwenda is innocent, too, Leo.
Do you?
Now, you...
You think that because you think
you know her character.
Well, I thought I knew Jacko's character
and I was wrong.
And it's character I've studied my whole life.
How history is not, erm...
an inevitable march of time,
but is shaped by the actions of
particular characters,
at...particular times.
How a king or politician's base motive
of greed, say, or jealousy, or ambition,
though ugly at the time has brought about
good things
when seen in the context of history.
You take...
You take the Medici, for example.
A despicable family,
capable of great cruelty,
yet their reign in Florence
produced economic prosperity
and art that has never been equalled.
- Good things can come out of bad deeds.
- Exactly.
And that's... That's what I thought...
..had happened when...
..Jacko killed Rachel.
MR LEO ARGYLE & MISS GWENDA VAUGHAN
How was London, Bob?
Any decisions on releasing
Mary's capital yet?
- Not now.
- We were promised a decision 18 months ago!
Look! I don't need this every time
I come back from London.
It's not your money!
I don't care if he's busy.
I want to see Inspector Huish now, please.
I've got vital information concerning
the Sunny Point murder
and I must tell him before he hangs
another innocent man.
Mrs Price, would you come this way, please?
Well, yes, but it's Cyril
you want to talk to, Inspector.
Cyril?
Cyril's come here to make a confession.
Haven't you, Cyril?
Yes.
Come on.
Cyril Price, did you bludgeon
Mrs Argyle to death?
No! He's been scrumping again.
I clipped him round the ear
and told him what for, Inspector.
But he was out scrumping
by the crossing to Sunny Point
on the night of the murder two years ago.
We would've come forward
but we thought you found...
What did you see, Cyril?
I saw...a dragon.
A what?
They call it that because of
the noise it makes
but he saw that motorbike.
Tina Argyle's bike.
He got back about 8.15,
so it must have been about 8.00
when he saw it.
So, what do you think about that, then?
She hasn't told you she was there
at the time of the murder, has she?
I told my husband the Inspector
wouldn't know this.
I said that to him, didn't I, Cyril?
Mm-hm?
Why do we always
have to play games, Bobby?
We can't just mope
around the house, can we?
- Are you...are you game, Mick?
- Sure.
Come on. You can be on my team.
I told you I didn't like this game, anyway.
- It's your serve.
- Come on. Come on, come on.
Is there any way that Philip and Jacko
could been in league?
I can't see it.
Well, they both wanted Rachel out of the way,
to get access to their fund.
They must have plotted this all along.
Something's happening.
Erm, Tina,
the Inspector would like a word.
Miss Argyle, will you come back
to the station, please?
- Why?
- For questioning.
What do you mean?
She's not going anywhere.
If you don't come up, I'll arrest you
on suspicion of involvement
in your mother's death.
- What are you talking about?
- It's all right.
She's done nothing wrong. Nothing wrong!
- Micky, it's all right.
- Dad!
She was at work in her library
at the time of the murder, wasn't she?
- I'm sure the police have their reasons.
- What reasons?
- What do they know, Dad?
- They didn't tell me.
- Why didn't you ask?
- Micky! Micky.
All of you...
The police are going to do their job
and there's nothing we can do.
All of us are under suspicion.
But we must stick together
and not let this drive us apart.
Now, I know...that none of you
could have committed murder.
I'm proud of all of you
and we will get through this.
I should say something here.
And it's what we're all thinking.
Mr Argyle, I know you are thinking it.
Which is why they have arrested Tina
and not arrested her.
- Absolutely.
- Am I not right?
Now, now...I'm not thinking that. No.
No, I am right.
And you have a duty now,
Gwenda Vaughan, to go and confess.
This family will not stand by
while another child swings
on the gallows for your crime.
- Did you do it, Gwenda?
- No.
No. Leo...
Leo!
- Leo, why don't you...
- I'm sorry. I...
We will not have a murderer
under this roof.
I am not a murderer!
And I'll be able to prove it!
I know things about this family and I swear...
What? What things?
What do you know?
I know that Rachel had given Philip
an ultimatum to leave Mary.
- What?
- Yes, because of your philandering.
She had a private detective onto you.
- Oh, this is preposterous.
- You see?
You see, this family's full of secrets.
But I know things
that will incriminate the killer.
I really do.
I'm in Rachel's room, remember?
I found things.
You've always maintained
that you were at work
in Redquay when
your mother was murdered.
Why have you been lying to us?
Why did you go to Sunny Point that night?
Mother had arranged for me
as assistant librarian
at St Andrew's University in Scotland.
I went to tell her I didn't want the job.
So you saw your mother that night?
I drove to Sunny Point but didn't cross.
Why not?
Why were you really there, Tina?
To see her about the job.
Then why didn't you?
Tina Argyle,
I'm holding you on suspicion
of being involved
in the murder of Rachel Argyle.
We'd have been on our honeymoon by now.
You can't throw around
accusations like that, Gwenda.
- People are accusing me.
- Gwenda...
They're accusing me.
I didn't do it, Leo. I didn't.
- Yes...
- Look me in the face
and tell me that you think I did it.
- Leo, look at me!
- Gwenda... Gwenda.
I think it's best if you move out
of Sunny Point tomorrow.
I think it's best for everyone
that I just have family here.
- Family?
- Yes.
Leo,
I am still the same person
that I was two days ago.
- I'm still the same woman...
- Yes.
..you wanted to be part of this family,
you wanted to marry.
I know, but I think it's best that you...
that you... leave here...in the morning.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Leave in the morning? What am...
- Night, Micky.
- Are you going down the police station?
They said to go in the morning.
- Miss Marple.
- Yes?
Miss Marple...
I don't know how to say this.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry for the things I said about her.
Gwenda?
She's been killed in the night.
You must be careful, Miss Marple.
If Gwenda found something out,
then maybe that's why she was killed.
And if she told you...
No.
She didn't.
- Nothing.
- You must be careful, Miss Marple.
I found her just before seven this morning.
I asked her to leave the house
today and I'd...
..taken her a cup of tea to wake her up.
I wanted her gone
before the children woke up.
We need to inform
Miss Vaughan's family of her death.
- Do you have...?
- She had no family.
This is where she thought
she'd found a family.
- I want my daddy!
- Hester.
I want my daddy!
- It's all right.
- I can't stand it any more.
- I know.
- I can't stand it.
- It's going to be fine.
- It's not going to be fine!
All right. All right, all right.
All right.
- Has she had her tablets?
- No, sir.
- Stay with me.
- Yes, I'll stay with you. Come on.
Come on, come on. Come on.
What weapon do you think was used,
if I may ask?
Well...
entry wound is very small. Pen knife, maybe.
A letter opener.
Daddy?
Daddy, what's happening?
It will be fine. You take care of Hester.
Make sure she's all right.
No, Miss Marple,
if I hadn't have come here,
none of this would have happened
and that poor girl would still be alive.
I blame myself.
I do, I do. I blame myself.
- Dr Calgary...
- I know It wasn't my fault, but...
really, I blame myself.
One can't help feeling that...
that...
Take me back to the Arctic.
That's where I belong.
Lemmings don't go round
murdering each other.
Pull yourself together, Dr Calgary.
There are some things I need you to do.
How are you?
Go away, Philip.
I'm just being nice.
You were never nice.
I think we may have a problem.
I think they might be onto us.
You can let Tina go,
now that you've arrested the old man,
can't you?
- Why can't you just let her go?!
- Hey, hey, hey.
Come on!
Are these yours?
I don't know how those
got into my room in that state.
- But they're yours? - Yes! Yes.
Mr Argyle, if you say
you didn't put these in your study,
you're implying that
a member of your family
is trying to frame you for murder.
When did you last see
Gwenda Vaughan alive?
Erm...in my study.
Last night, at about eleven o'clock.
And when did your relatlonship
with her begin?
Erm...about erm...
..four months after my wife died.
Gwenda was very...
..kind.
She was...
..loving in a way...
..in a way that no-one ever had been...
..loving...
Oh, Gwenda.
Have you read Leo's book?
He was talking to me about it.
And this is what it's all about, isn't it?
Did he talk to you, Miss Marple?
"Good things come from bad deeds."
- Kirsten.
- No, it has to be said.
He was a shadow of a man with Rachel
and when she died, he became alive
again, didn't he, Mary?
Yes.
And he'd never loved Jacko
like we did Bob.
And he'd already started his affair
with Gwenda.
I'm the eyes of this house.
I see what I'm not supposed to see.
Mrs Lindsay.
- Mrs Lindsay.
- Where's your car, love?
I can't go filling you up with petrol.
My... My car?
- It was a joke.
- Right. Right! Yes, I understand it.
Mrs Lindsay, I wondered if I could
have a rather delicate word with you.
Jacko. What a boy.
He was the kind of bloke who could get
under skin, you know?
Naughty. Dangerous.
You knew you shouldn't but...
He was like a drug.
He could make you feel 22 again.
You ever had a girl like that,
Professor?
There was a young erm...
young lady at...church once,
but we never really...spoke.
What was her name?
I... I believe erm...
I believe you gave
Jacko Argyle some money.
I knew what he was up to.
He pinched a wad off my husband and
needed to pay him back.
And you knew about this and yet you...
went along with it.
I didn't want him to go away.
Ever.
Even though you knew you weren't
the only one,
even though you knew he was
gonna end badly...
I went up to the prison once,
where they were holding him.
He wouldn't see me.
Yet I cried like a child
the day they hanged him.
Even now.
Miss Marple.
Can we talk?
I know who killed Gwenda.
I know who killed Mother but
I have no evidence.
I don't think the police will believe me.
Will you believe me?
What do you know?
Miss Marple,
who's the weakest in this family?
Who have they always tried to protect,
especially from Mother?
And who followed Jacko out
the night of the murder?
Jacko!
Jacko, wait!
Mother had been bullying
Hester for years.
And Hester adored Jacko.
Would've killed for him, I'm sure.
You know what they say about timid people
when pushed to violence.
And now she's killed Gwenda
because Gwenda said she'd
discovered the truth.
Mary, why did you tell the police
you were with Philip
when your mother was murdered,
and yet yesterday you told me
you left the big house
much earlier that evening?
Hester's a very attractive girl,
isn't she, Mary?
Would you want the world to know
your husband was sleeping
with your sister?
I lied to the police, Miss Marple,
because I have a sense of shame.
But it doesn't change the fact
that Hester did this...
and she's now trying to frame
my father for murder.
- Hello.
- Sir.
- May I have my key, please?
- Certainly.
Yes, sir.
Oh, sir, you forgot your key.
Going to London, Bobby, on a Sunday?
Your father might need you today.
You're not my keeper, Philip.
Now, listen, you little chump.
According to my calculations,
Mary's share of the trust
should be a quarter of a million.
I know we've asked for 20 grand
to buy a house,
but I think we should have all of it now
and we should stop being treated
like children!
Known the condition was the trust, Philip.
- You are entitled to half...
- Yes, but when, Bob?
Bobby.
Bobby!
Miss Argyle.
Miss Argyle?
Why don't we...
go back to the house?
I know what I wanted to ask you...
..Dr Scientist.
You know about animals
and environments, don't you?
You take an animal
out of its environment
and it suffers, doesn't it?
It dies inside.
Zoos try and reinvent it but...
- Mr Argyle!
- ..they die inside.
Mr Argyle, can you help us?
Even animals need love, Dr Scientist.
If we just...step away from the water...
I'll be more than willing to give you
seminar on the subject
..back at the house.
Probably even... I'll set up a slide show.
Money is the cause of this family's misery.
All of us were from poor backgrounds.
Yes. Yes, that's lovely.
If you can just step away...
- Money has not made us happy.
- It never does.
Animals don't have money, do they?
Not a penny.
Why is that?
Why have human beings
turned unhappiness
into coins that you can actually touch?
Where's Bobby?
Bobby!
No!
- Bobby!
- Miss Argyle!
- No!
Bobby!
I don't think you're going to find
a suicide note, inspector.
That is what you're looking for, isn't it?
A confession.
Why won't I find one?
'Cause I don't think Bobby
really intended to kill himself.
At least...not until he was
halfway over the crossing.
What do you know, Miss Marple?
I think it's something the whole
family should hear.
It seems...that despite their differences,
the twins Bobby and Jacko
were more alike than anybody realised.
It always struck me as odd
that Bobby was as parsimonious
with the trust as Rachel had been,
that since she died,
he had barely parted with a penny.
But I think...
Bobby had been living under great stress.
So I asked Dr Calgary
to get in touch with his stockbrokers,
Marshalls.
Yes. Yes, well...
Erm...one of partners of Marshalls
was arrested this morning
for fraud and embezzlement
and it seems that he and Bobby
had their fingers
in the honey pot, so to speak.
Bobby used Rachel's trust for
financial scams
on a much larger scale than Jacko
ever got involved in.
The authorities had been closing in
on his corruption for the last two years.
Which means that Rachel, as a trustee,
would have had knowledge
of Bobby's criminal activities
shortly before she died.
Sort it out yourself, Bobby!
Sometimes I feel I should never
have bothered
with you and your brother.
But Bobby's always been
as generous as he could with us.
- Yes.
- He was paying for this whole wedding.
With money he didn't have.
Yes, it seems that for the last two years...
he'd been trying to keep
one step ahead of financial ruin.
Robbing Peter to pay Paul.
And I think love he put into the wedding
was a last attempt
to keep the good times at Sunny Point.
You're telling me that...
Bobby murdered Rachel
when she found out about the fraud?
Bobby's about the only member of
the family you never arrested,
inspector Huish,.
That's enough of that.
No doubt you'd have got round to him.
Bobby was no more a killer
than his brother was.
He'd been genuinely troubled
by Jacko's last words.
Maybe this is the best thing...
I've ever done.
And why offer up information like that
if you were intent on Jacko
being blamed for the murder?
Why not, for example, try and...
discredit Dr Calgary's evidence?
And, besides, he wasn't the only person
who benefited from
Rachel's death that night,
was he, Mr Durrant?
Your secrets were kept safe.
Tina, why did your mother arrange
for you to have a job
at a university library
in the north of Scotland?
She doesn't know. OK?
Mum was a very controlling woman.
Let her answer, please.
When you came here that night
to tell her
you weren't going to take the position,
who did you see coming over the crossing
just after the time of the murder?
Whose boat was being used, Tina?
Micky's.
No, I was at work.
I was collecting from Bristol.
You checked that with my employer,
didn't you, Inspector?
I didn't stay because if Micky
was in a temper,
as he usually was after visiting Mother,
he'd be in no mood to talk to me.
Why did you think Micky
had come to see your mother?
He was angry with her.
He didn't want her to keep controlling my life.
Why not?
She'd realised you and Micky
were in relationship, hadn't she?
While you both lived away in Redquay
and she was determined
to drive a wedge between you.
We're only brother and sister by law.
She had no right to control us.
Micky.
You suspect Micky killed your mother,
don't you, Tina?
You're trying to protect him.
Miss Marple, his alibi does check out
with his employers.
You saw Micky's boat and thought it was him.
But it couldn't have been Micky
rowing, Tina.
You...
..followed Jacko out that night,
didn't you, Hester?
What did you talk about?
Nothing.
I'm a dead man, Hes.
Calm down. Let's go for a walk, baby.
If I don't get the cash...
they really are going to kill me.
I'm sure it's not that bad, Jacko.
What do you know?
I'd never seen Jacko frightened.
I couldn't calm him.
How far dld you walk with him?
Just to the corner of the house.
Then I came back.
Did you see anyone else?
No.
Are you sure?
Because I don't think
you were the only one
who followed Jacko out after the fight
Who, then?
Who has been shifting the blame
from one person to another
since Dr Calgary's arrival?
Jacko is responsible.
I'm certain.
Thank God you have
not yet married her, Mr Argyle!
Thank God she will not get away with it.
He was a shadow of a man with Rachel.
When she died, he became alive again.
Who considers herself to be
the real mother of children,
the one who gave them
the unconditional love
they were so badly short of?
For what reason would I
follow Jacko out, Miss Marple?
Because you loved him.
Because you were the latest
in a long line
of middle-aged women Jacko
could manipulate,
Jacko could bleed dry of savings,
Jacko could make feel...special.
You said Jacko killed Rachel
and I think you still believe that.
You believe that Jacko was responsible.
Make it look like a burglary
and then bring me the money.
Yes.
And hit her hard.
Make sure she'll never get up.
I'll get a cast iron alibi for eight o'clock
because everyone will suspect it's me.
Eight o'clock.
Yes, my darling.
Jacko did know who the real killer was,
but he also knew that if he left prison...
he was going to get killed, anyway.
And he did the one good thing in his life
by letting you go free.
The real mother that these children had.
You tell a good story, Miss Marple.
But what proof is there?
No-one saw anything.
No-one heard anything.
Not even inspector Huish
can arrest me on hearsay.
These children, who you've loved
and protected all your life,
will never be free of suspicion
if you don't confess, Kirsten.
Their ordeal by innocence
has already cost one of them his life
and another has been pushed to the edge.
Let alone my friend...
whose life you thought disposable,
who was not part of this family,
who was never part of any family
and who you...denied happiness to.
Set your children free, Kirsten.
It's the only way
you can protect them now.
Kirsten Lindstrom, did you murder
Rachel Argyle and Gwenda Vaughan?
If she loved Jacko so much...
why did she let him die?
She didn't know about him being married.
She thought she was the only one.
I think her love curdled to hate
the moment
his wife knocked on the door.
- Are you going to London?
- Yes.
Then I'm travelling again to Galapagos,
with new expedition.
Do you ever go home, Dr Calgary?
Rarely. Rarely.
Where's home for you, Miss Marple?
Home.
Home is St Mary Mead.
I must say, what I'm looking forward to
about the Galapagos
is seeing species
that are peculiar to those islands.
Don't you think it would be a remarkable thing,
to stumble, like Darwin, across islands
that contain new kinds?
Yes, I do.
-==http://www.ragbear.com==-